Career Objective

To leverage over ten years of IT experience and military training to secure a career In software engineering where I can exercise and improve my attention to detail, understanding of hardware and software relationships, ability to work alone or as a team and expand my knowledge.

Work Experience

GEORGIA AIR NATION GUARD, SAVANNAH, GA

Cyber Transport Technician 2008 - Present

- Design and configure connections with military/commercial protocols and multiplexers
- Develop video, data and voice network design and configurations for computer and telecommunications systems to support in-garrison
- Install equipment and connections for both secure and non secure networks
- Evaluate equipment for serviceability and completeness after installation
- Organize and conduct operational tests and evaluations of designed network architecture to monitor and optimize network capacity and performance capabilities
- Perform collection and analysis of data from customer log to create trend and performance reports along with future requirements for the information management area
- Fabricate cables and connectors to interface with various commercial and military electronic systems
- Make decisions and recommendations for optimum network performance quality
- Research trends and patterns to apply new or improved communication methods and procedures

ROCKSTAR ENERGY DRINK - SAVANNAH, GA

Sales Representative Oct 2019-Present

- Call upon convenience store, package store and grocery store accounts for extra sales and to ensure distributor is complying with terms set up by contract
- Manage time professionally to ensure quota is maintained in a set period of time on a daily basis
- Perform daily inspections of vehicle and material to ensure goal can be completed
- Responsible for selling 25 products
- Performed onsite, in-store retail sales

UNITED DISTRIBUTORS, SAVANNAH, GA

Sales Trainee May 2017- Oct 2019

- Call upon accounts for convenience store, package store and grocery store accounts for various duties
- Merchandise and face all product while maintaining rotation and in-date products
- Increase over all sales by knowing United Distributors portfolio of beer and wine
- Perform store resets in accordance with federal law
- Conduct all business and sales with a positive disposition and professional attitude

Driver Associate - AP/BP Permit October 2016 – May 2017

 Build and ensure excellent customer service by consistently delivering orders on time and in good condition and by acting in a courteous and professional manner

SAVANNAH DISTRIBUTING CO, SAVANNAH, GA

IT Specialist/Beer Bon Vivant/ Inventory Management/AP Assistant 2012 - 2015

- Install, maintain, administer and troubleshoot various network devices and problems to ensure proper function of computers, network and route accounting systems
- Network with supplier representatives and customers forming a professional and friendly relationship while loyally supporting brands and products provided by the company
- Setup new route accounting system and mobile devices for a system upgrade
- Manage inventory to ensure inventory numbers are correct and product does not go out of date
- Compare invoices with receiving to ensure the proper payment is made to supplier
- Order and receive products in the route accounting system

SPIKES PC & IT LLC, SAVANNAH, GA

Owner/Lead Technician 2012 - 2013

- Market services to new clients and maintain relationships with established clients to promote referrals and build the company's reputation
- Analyze client systems and make recommendations for improving network efficiency
- Install, maintain and troubleshoot networks and PCs for residential and business clients
- Researching new advances in technology and keeping clients informed on security threats
- Managing the finances and resources of the company to maximize profit and growth
- Designing service packages for clients

FAST-TEKS ONSITE COMPUTER REPAIR, SAVANNAH, GA

Lead Technician 2011 – 2012

- Onsite setup, installation, maintenance and support of computers and networks for business and residential clients
- Networking with potential referral sources to generate new business at BNI meetings and events
- Up-selling services and memberships to clients to maximize profit and increase repeat business
- Creating service and sales invoices and collection of payments from clients

SEIMITSU, SAVANNAH, GA

IT Technician/ Engineer 2010-2011

- Initial setup, installation, maintenance and support of network infrastructures, closed circuit televisions and VoIP telephones systems
- PC Repair
- Program and service wireless radios for eSavannah wireless internet in the Savannah area
- Strengthen relationships with existing clients by communication and problem solving

Education

SOUTH EFFINGHAM HIGH SCHOOL GUYTON, GA

High School Diploma, May 2004

UNITED STATES AIR FORCE, BILOXI, MS

- Network Infrastructure Systems, 2009
- Electronic Principles, 2009
- TDC Voice Communications, 2009
- CompTIA Security+, 2011
- Georgia Tech Coding Boot Camp, 2020

Additional Skills

- Route Accounting Systems
- Marketing
- HTML
- JavaScript

- Inventory Management
- Networking
- CSS
- JQuery

- Customer Relations
- Sales
- Bootstrap
- NodeJS